# **Suraj Gurung**

NJ 08854 |3477572850 | Microbiosuraj@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/grgsuraj/| https://surajbgurung.github.io/responsivePortfolio/https://github.com/surajbgurung

## **SUMMARY**

Recently graduated from Rutgers University Coding Bootcamp, motivated and passionate Developer with excellent written and verbal communication skills and have experience in all stages of web development such as requirement gathering, designing, development, testing, deployment and maintenance. Highly proficient in a wide variety of scripting languages, databases, and full-stack development tools.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Languages:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript **Databases:** MySQL, MongoDB

Frameworks: Bootstrap, JQuery, Node.js, Express.js, React, Handlebars, Mongoose

General: Microsoft office, Powerpoints, spreadsheets, Git/Github

**PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE** 

# Freelance Photographer (Self-employed) (2010-2020)

- Leveraged extensive knowledge of photography in portrait, event and candid shots
- Take high quality shots for clients to fulfills their requirements
- Build strong client relations leading to repeat business

Chauffeur (Self-employee, Taxi and Limousine commission NYC (uber) ) (2016-2020)

- Courteous in all driving and non-driving situations while on the job
- Act professional and friendly to passengers at all times
- Received average rating of 4.88

Trainee Microbiologist: Shree Birendra Hospital (Nepalese Army Hospital) (2012-2013)

• Direct detection of pathogenic organisms by microscopy and molecular techniques

### **NOTABLE PROJECT**

Portfolio-Builder Github(https://bit.ly/34rQJd1) Deployed (https://bit.ly/3jagF0R) (August 2020)

- Portfolio builder is an interactive online portfolio template that allows you to plug in information and build a cohesive portfolio.
- Used tools MongoDB, Express, React and Node with JSON Web Token encrypted login

GetMed Github (https://bit.ly/31mi0vu) Deployed (https://bit.ly/3j7CSwu) (June 2020)

- A web application that acts as a pharmacy e-commerce site and delivery service.
- Utilize MySQL database with Sequelize models hook associations, and encrypted login information for customer and driver on the same browser.

Music Venue Planner Github (https://bit.ly/32kRqC3) Deployed (https://bit.ly/2ZuUPgZ) (April 2020)

- Search music events and concerts in New York City and plan the event through five day weather Forecast
- Used tools such as HTML, CSS, GitHub and GitBash, APIs, AJAX, JS, jQuery, Bootstrap

## **EDUCATION**

Certificate in Full Stack Development, (Aug 2020)
Rutgers University, New Jersey

MSc in Medical Microbiology, (2009-2011)
St.Xavier's College, Maitighar, Nepal